Cristina Marban
Dr. Lam
TECM 5191
25 September 2015

	How William Hart-Davidson’s article Content Management: Beyond Single-Sourcing altered my perspective on Technical Communicators role within an organization is that I learned that even though technical communicators are known as writers, editors, and illustrators, they can also expand their roles in the profession of content management. For example, they can become project managers or information analysts because they have experience in writing and researching different types of information documents. However, technical communicators only view content management as single sourcing which is the process of producing and distributing content in many formats from one repository. I think that technical communicators are afraid of content management because they believe that content management will take their jobs, since people who work in information economy will begin to write and people in computer technologies will begin to edit and design documents like manuals, brochures, etc. Although, technology changed the way technical communicators complete and produce their work during the 1980s and 1990s, I liked how they adapted themselves to the new technology because they started to create electronic documents, computer software, and tools that people can use. Furthermore, I think it is great that technical communicators are filling different roles in different organizations like engineering, business, and computer industries as project, or content managers, information architects, usability analysts, etc  because they have enough experience in writing, editing , and designing different types of information documents.  Subsequently, technical communicators should not be afraid of losing their profession because their skills are important for the progress and success of different organizations since they research what their audience is looking for in various information documents. Finally, technical communicators should expand their roles at the organizations they work for because they are better at writing, outlining, checking, and improving documents before producing the documents to the audience they are targeting.
