Cristina Marban
TECM 5191
30 August 2015
Response Paper

	  When I finished reading the article, Do Curricula Correspond to Managerial Expectations by Rainey and Dayton, I was surprised about how the 67 managers of technical communication ranked the core competencies and skills that new technical communicators need to succeed in their careers and how they differ from what the curriculum of the 10 largest undergraduate technical communication programs are teaching. For example, I thought it was interesting that the managers were more concerned if the new technical communicators were willing to learn how to use all the different software programs quickly, instead of being apprehensive if they were not knowledgeable about the latest technology tools. Usually, when I read job ads for technical writers, most of the employers require the applicant to have experience in knowing how to use software programs and other technology tools. However, I am glad that it’s not true because not all English and technical communication college programs have a lot of courses that teach how to use all of software programs and tools like “FrameMaker.”Also, it was puzzling that the managers of technical communication ranked teamwork and working with subject-matter experts as the most important competency for technical communicators, instead of writing and editing skills. Since, technical writers need to write in a concise and understanding manner to attract the attention of a specific audience. Furthermore, I found it strange that the lower ranked competencies were “the ability to make oral presentations” because in college we are assigned to make oral presentations accompanied by a PowerPoint presentation. Most of all, I was taken aback that the ability to create websites was one of the lower-ranked competencies because a lot of technical writers have to create professional web sites for the companies they work for to attract more business. In addition, many of the English courses and technical communication courses, we have to learn to create websites. Finally, I do believe that undergraduate technical communication programs should pay attention to the skills professional technical communicators are looking for in new employers, so the students can be prepared for their future careers.
