Cristina Marban
Dr. Lam
TECM 5191
12 September 2015

The article of Jan H. Spyridakis is trying to identify what new topics the Technical Communication curriculum can teach to the students, so they will be prepared to succeed in the ever progressing careers of technical communicators. While Saul Carliner’s article, Computers and Technical Communication in the 21st Century was about how the technology of computers changed the way the technical communicators produced their work. Also, Carliner’s article concentrates on how technology changed technical communication’s jobs and job titles in the computer industry. Above all, as technology progressed, technical communicators were no longer called, or seen as just writers, editors, and illustrators because they were learning how to create software , tools, and databases on computers. Furthermore, technical communicators were also getting more computer science degrees, so they could develop their skill and work for the computer industries. However, Spyridakis’ article focuses more on finding new topics that the Technical Communication curriculum can teach to students that will become technical communicators in the future. In addition, Spyridakis does not concentrate a lot about technology tools and software being taught in college because she knows that technology is always changing and new software tools are always being created. Both of these articles seem to agree that technical communicators should evolve and begin to gain content management and business skills to produce their work. There are some differences and similarities between Spyridakis’ article and Albers’ article, The Future of Technical Communication. For example, Spyridakis’ believes that the technical communication curriculum should include new courses that teach new topics like what UX researchers and designers do, genres, management skills, business skills, collaboration skills, and tools, so future communicators will be prepared for the different career roles they will have in technical communication. Also, Spyridakis did more investigation on what topics could be taught by reviewing technical communication discussions, surveys about the technical communication curriculum, technical communication job titles, etc. Albers’ describes how writers in the technical communication field spend a lot of time trying to write perfect prose instead of worrying about the audience they are targeting. Meanwhile, both authors are worried about the future of technical communication, how collaboration and project management skills are important to have because technical communicators have to take on new roles since technical communication is always changing due to technology and the different facilities they are surrounded by. It is interesting that they are both worried about the same things because one article was published in 2005 and the other one was published in 2015. Thirdly, the difference between Spyridakis’ article and R. Stanley Dick’s article, The Effects of Digital Literacy on the Nature of Technical Communication Work is that Dick explains how the economy, management principles, and methodologies like WEB 2.0 and single sourcing changed the way technical communicators work. Moreover, both articles explore implications for education and training due to the new focus on symbolic-analytic work among technical communicators.   
Although, the Spyridakis article and the Rainey, Dayton, and Turner’s article cover some similar topics, Spyridakis’ expands her research in different ways to find new topics that can be included in the technical communication curricula, so students can be prepared for their future careers. Well, Rainey, Dayton, and Turner’s article only describes how the 67 managers of technical communication ranked the core competencies and skills that future technical communicators need to succeed in their careers and how they differ from what the curriculum of the 10 largest undergraduate technical communication programs are teaching. In Spyridakis’ core competencies section, she describes how Rainey, Dayton, and Turner had to  survey 67 technical communication managers and evaluate the curriculum of the 10 largest technical communication undergraduate programs to identify the main competencies and skills that is expected of technical communication graduates. She also explains that the skills they ranked as less important are now in more demand in the technical communication industry. Above all, Spyridakis looks at job ads and job titles to see what skills employers are looking for in technical communicators to see what new courses the curriculum of technical communication should create.  Similarly, the Spyridakis’ article and the Anderson article agree that technical communication should collaborate with other fields like engineering because it is important to evolve the different careers of technical communicators. They also believe that the most important skill technical communicators should have are management skills because they need to know how to manage other workers and the way they produce work. Nevertheless, Anderson focuses more on how content management has impacted technical communication and how the era of document and information development is ending because more people are reading documents, articles, books, etc online. Subsequently, while Spyridakis’ focuses on topics that should be taught in technical communication college programs, the Anthony article focuses more on AntConc, a tool that is a corpus analysis toolkit designed for specific use in the classroom, it also explains the inadequacies of the tool and how they will be improved in the future.  Finally, Spyridakis’ thinks that tools are not an as important as other topics to teach because it is more important to be willing to learn tools quickly since new tools are always being created. 

